Finding Aid for the Lawrence Clark Powell Papers LSC.0229
UCLA Library Special Collections
- J. Frank Dobie
  - Publications
    - Dobie, J. Frank [Guest Columnist]. Column in Houston Post, July 1955.; (Ditto typescript, 3 leaves) (Box 10, Folder 26)
      Also, postcard.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. A Man Named Dobie. Printed by the Bookman Press for the First Joint Meeting of the Zamorano Club and the Los Angeles Westerners. Los Angeles, December 1, 1954. (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Dobie, J. Frank. His Looks and My Ways Would Hang Any Man. In Southwest Review (vol.41, no.3), Summer 1956. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Christmas, the Southwest, and J. Frank Dobie. In J.E. Reynolds' A Holiday Catalog, Western Americana, 1956. (Box 10, Folder 29)
      [Book dealer's catalogue].
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Christmas, the Southwest, and J. Frank Dobie. Van Nuys, California: Westernlore Press, Christmas 1956. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Mr. Southwest: J. Frank Dobie of Texas. In Arizona Highways (vol.33, no.6), June 1957. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Dobie, J. Frank. For Years We Three Sat Together. In The Texas Observer (vol.55, no.17), July 26, 1963. (Box 10, Folder 32)
      See also material under J. Frank Dobie in the Southwest Emphemera Collection, Number 360.
- Southwest Broadsides
  - Manuscripts
    - Southwest Broadsides., (Three carbon copy typescripts on onion skin, [6] leaves) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The Southwest Broadsides; printed for the friends of Lawrence Clark Powell (1-12), Los Angeles, 1953-1958. 1958.; (Carbon copy typescript on yellow onion skin, [15] leaves) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from Various Persons, v.d.
      - 1949-1955. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - 1956. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - 1957-1958. (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - 1959-1961. (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Letters to various persons from Lawrence Clark Powell, 1955-1960. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Letters to and from various persons, 1955-1958, and n.d. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous--Newspaper articles, lists, etc. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Publications
    - Southwest Broadsides (no.1-12), Edited by Lawrence Clark Powell [Various Printers]., 1953-1958. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      The Southwest Broadsides were printed for the friends of Lawrence Clark Powell. Issued irregularly.
      See Box 120 for no.6, 11 and 12.
    - The Southwest Broadsides; printed for the friends of Lawrence Clark Powell, 1953-1958. Los Angeles: Printed by Will Cheney (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Books of the Southwest
  - Publication
    - Books of the Southwest. A Critical Checklist of Current Southwestern Americana. Compiled by Lawrence Clark Powell. Published by the Library of the University of California, Los Angeles. (no.1-to date), [Issued Monthly]., June 1957-. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      A complete file of this publication is in the stacks of the Department of Special Collections. The call number is Z1251, S8B7.
- Heart of the Southwest
  - Manuscripts and Typescripts
    - Heart of the Southwest; a selective bibliography of novels, stories and tales laid in Arizona and New Mexico and adjacent lands., (Holograph Manuscript in pencil, [153] leaves) (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Also includes holograph and typescript bibliography entries on 3 × 5 paper slips, [173] leaves.
    - Heart of the Southwest; a selective bibliography of novels, stories and tales, laid in Arizona and New Mexico and adjacent lands., (Typescript on sulfide bond, [136] leaves) (Box 12, Folder 2)
      With holograph corrections and other manuscript notes including the holograph notes of J. Frank Dobie on the last 15 leaves of the typescript.
    - Heart of the Southwest; a selective bibliography of novels, stories and tales laid in Arizona and New Mexico and adjacent lands., (Carbon copy typescript on onion skin, [123] leaves) (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Used as a working copy with notes by Wilbur J. Smith and Leo Linder.
      Also, notes on p-slips (3 leaves).
      There is 1 leaf missing, no.20
    - Heart of the Southwest; a selective bibliography of novels, stories and tales laid in Arizona and New Mexico and adjacent lands., ([138] leaves) (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Printer's copy (corrected typescript draft) with some holograph corrections.
      The original typescript was published by Dawson's Bookshop, 1955.
      Revised for publication in Arizona Highways in 1956.
  - Galley Proofs
    - Heart of the Southwest; a selective bibliography of novels, stories and tales laid in Arizona and New Mexico and adjacent lands., ([15] leaves) (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Galley Proofs with holograph corrections.
  - Correspondence and Notes
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons and correspondence and notes, 1956-. (Box 12, Folder 6)
      re the acquisition of the titles in Lawrence Clark Powell's Bibliography, Heart of the Southwest.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, catalogs, etc. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Publications
    - Heart of the Southwest; a selective bibliography of novels, stories and tales laid in Arizona and New Mexico and adjacent lands. Los Angeles: Dawson's Book Shop, 1955. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Heart of the Southwest; a selective reading list of good novels and stories mostly with settings in Arizona and New Mexico. In Arizona Highways (vol.33, no.2), February 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Revised and Enlarged.
- Books West Southwest
  - Manuscripts
    - Books West Southwest., ([181] leaves plus [5]pp.) (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Printer's copy with some holograph corrections.
    - Books West Southwest., (A partial carbon copy typescript, [72] leaves) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Galley Proofs
    - Books West Southwest., ([51] leaves) (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Galley Proofs with holograph and publisher's corrections.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Book Review. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Publication
    - Books West Southwest: Essays on Writers, Their Books and Their Land. Los Angeles: Ward Ritchie Press, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence with various persons, 1957-. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Libros Californianos
  - Manuscripts
    - Hanna, Phil Townsend. Libros Californianos or Five Feet of California Books., (A photostatic copy of Hanna's original book, 74pp.; typescript [35] leaves; a manuscript note on printing instructions, 1 leaf; and a printed Preface, 2pp.) (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Revised and enlarged by Lawrence Clark Powell.
      A working copy with corrections by Lawrence Clark Powell and others.
  - Galleys and Page Proofs
    - Hanna, Phil Townsend. Libros Californianos or Five Feet of California Books., August 19, 1958.; (21 leaves) (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Galley Proof.
      With notes and corrections by Lawrence Clark Powell and others.
    - Hanna, Phil Townsend. Libros Californianos or Five Feet of California Books., August 19, 1958.; (21 leaves) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Hanna, Phil Townsend. Libros Californianos or Five Feet of California Books., September 22, 1958.; (45 leaves) (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Page Proofs.
      With corrections by Lawrence Clark Powell.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Prospectus, etc. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Publication
    - Hanna, Phil Townsend. Libros Californianos or Five Feet of California Books. Los Angeles: Zeitlin and Ver Brugge, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- A Passion for Books
  - Manuscripts
    - A Passion for Books., (226 leaves) (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Printer's typescript copy with some holograph corrections.
  - Galleys and Page Proofs
    - A Passion for Books., ([77] leaves) (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Galley proof with holograph and publisher's and other corrections.
    - A Passion for Books., ([11] leaves and [2] typescript leaves) (Box 15, Folder 3)
      3 copies of page proofs for the preliminary and final pages with holograph and publisher's corrections.
    - A Passion for Books., (249pp. or [83] leaves) (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Page proofs with holograph and publisher's corrections.
    - A Passion for Books., (249pp.) (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Page proofs of the special edition.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Book reviews, etc. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Publications
    - A Passion for Books. Cleveland and New York: the World Publishing Company, 1958.; (249pp. and 3 unnumbered pages) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - A Passion for Books. London: Constable and Company Limited, 1959.; (249pp. and 3 unnumbered pages) (Box 16, Folder 4)
      For correspondence, see Box 73.
- Books in My Baggage
  - Manuscripts
    - Books in My Baggage., ([309] leaves) (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Publisher's typescript with holograph notes and corrections.
  - Galley and Page Proofs
    - Books in My Baggage., ([77] leaves) (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Galley proof with publisher's, holograph and other corrections.
    - Books in My Baggage., ([76] leaves) (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Galley proof with holograph corrections.
    - Books in My Baggage., ([83] leaves) (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Page proofs with publisher's, some holograph, and other corrections.
    - Books in My Baggage., ([5] leaves) (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Galleys and page proofs of the title pages with printing instructions.
    - Books in My Baggage., ([8] leaves) (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Typescript and page proofs of the copyright page with holograph corrections and printing instructions.
    - Books in My Baggage., ([40] leaves) (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Miscellaneous page proofs with holograph and other corrections.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Prospectus, notices, etc. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Publication
    - Books in my Baggage, Adventures in Reading and Collecting. Cleveland and New York: the World Publishing Company, 1960.; (255pp. and 3 unnumbered pages) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence with William Targ, Editor-in-chief of World Publishing Company, 1959-1960. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with various persons, 1960-1969 (Box 18, Folder 7-7a)
      - A - I. (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - J - Z. (Box 18, Folder 7a)
    - Reviews. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Sydney B. Mitchell
  - Research Material
    - A Bibliography of Sydney B. Mitchell and his various publications., (Manuscript on 3 × 5 paper slips, [66] leaves) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - A Bibliography of Sydney B. Mitchell and his various publications., (Typescript on 5.5 × 8.5 blue paper sheets, [31] leaves) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. All in a Lifetime., (Bound ledger book, 184pp.) (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Notes for an autobiography.
      With notes scattered throughout.
      [Title changed to: On My Way]
    - California Library Association--California Library History Committe., February 17, 1950.; (Typescript with corrections, 15 leaves) (Box 19, Folder 4)
      A Wire-Recorded Interview with Sydney B. Mitchell, Berkeley, California.
  - Manuscripts
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. On My Way. Essays in Recollection of Early Life in Canada, later in California, of Librarianship and of Gardening., ([154] leaves) (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Incomplete typescript with corrections--one rewritten chapter and missing pages. One holograph page also included.
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. Mitchell at Large. The Memoirs of Sydney B. Mitchell-Librarian, Gardener, Teacher., (16pp.) (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Typescript with 4 manuscript pages and some corrections by Lawrence Clark Powell. Other corrections present (208 leaves).
      Also included: Sydney B. Mitchell, Dean of Horticulture in California, by Cora R. Brandt (A reprint from the Journal of the California Horticultural Society, April and July 1960).
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. Mitchell at Large. The Memoirs of Sydney B. Mitchell, Librarian, Gardener, Teacher., (Typescript, 246 leaves) (Box 19, Folder 7)
      The original form of the typescript with the Preface by Andrew H. Horn although the title page reads Preface by Lawrence Clark Powell.
      With some corrections.
    - Horn, Andrew H. Foreword to Mitchell at Large., (Typescript, 3 leaves) (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Preface to Mitchell at Large., (Typescript, 2 leaves) (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Mitchell of California., (Typescript, 8 leaves) (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. The Library School at Berkeley. In Mitchell at Large., (Carbon copy typescript, 14 leaves) (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Galleys
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. Mitchell of California. The Memoirs of Sydney B. Mitchell, Librarian, Gardener, Teacher. Preface by Lawrence Clark Powell., (95 leaves) (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Galley proof with corrections.
      [Title changed from Mitchell at Large]..
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. Mitchell of California. The Memoirs of Sydney B. Mitchell, Librarian, Gardener, Teacher. Preface by Lawrence Clark Powell., (95 leaves) (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Also included, typescript of galley corrections (3 leaves).
  - Correspondence
    - Letters and notes to and from various persons, 1954- and n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Obituary of Sydney B. Mitchell and in memoriam essays, etc. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Publications
    - Mitchell, Sydney B. Mitchell of California. The Memoirs of Sydney B. Mitchell, Librarian--Teacher--Gardener. With a Preface by Lawrence Clark Powell. Berkeley, California: Library Association, 1960.; (263pp.) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Mitchell of California. A reprint from the Wilson Library Bulletin ()., May 1954; ([5]pp.) (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Robinson Jeffers
  - Typescript and Galley Proofs
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers. Los Angeles: Los Angeles City College Press, 1950.; (21 leaves) (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Printer's typescript with holograph corrections.
      Also galley proof with holograph corrections (7 leaves).
  - Correspondence
    - Letters to and from various persons, 1935-. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Book reviews of Powell's works on Jeffers, etc. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Publications
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers: The Man and His Work (3rd revised edition). Foreword by Robinson Jeffers; decorations by Jack Hawkins. Pasadena, California: San Pasqual Press, 1940.; (222pp.) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers on Life and Letters. Westways (vol.26, no.4), March 1934. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers, `05. In The Occidental Alumnus (vol.17, no.1), March 1935. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers, 1905-1935; an Exhibition Commemorating the Thirtieth Anniversary of his graduation from Occidental College, Los Angeles, California, April 11 to 18. Los Angeles: Ward Ritchie (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers and His Garden. In Sunset (vol.74, no.5), May 1935. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. The Man at Tor House. In Vo-mag (vol.4, no.2), March 1936. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers. In Montevallo Review, Summer 1950. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Robinson Jeffers: a Lecture to Professor James L. Wortham's Class in Narrative Poetry given on May 22, 1949. Los Angeles: The Press of Los Angeles City College, 1951. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. [Foreword to] Robinson Jeffers at Occidental College. A Checklist of the Jeffers Collection in the Mary Norton Clapp Library. Published on the Fiftieth Anniversary of Graduation, June 1955. Los Angeles: The Ward Ritchie Press (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. The Double Marriage of Robinson Jeffers. Reprinted from Southwest Review (vol.41, no.3) Summer 1956. (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Islandia
  - Research Material
    - Notes, clippings, biographical material, etc. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Photostats from John K. Wright's journal,; photostated and original letters from Austin T. Wright to his brother, John, 1913 1930 and n.d. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Typescripts
    - Bacon, Leonard. Austin Wright and His Strange Story., (Typescript, 20 leaves) (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Unpublished.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. All That Is Poetic in Life. Austin Wright's Islandia., (Typescript, 12 leaves) (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Austin Wright's Islandia., (13 leaves) (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Islandia; Wisdom of the Heart. A Lecture to Professor Kinsman's Class in Utopia and Anti-Utopia, UCLA, January 11, 1956., (Ditto typescript, 15 leaves) (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Also, [1] leaf course outline.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Introduction to An Islandian of the Islands, a Field Report by Austin T. Wright, Author of Islandia on the Southern California Islands of Santa Rosa and Santa Cruz, written in a letter to his brother, John K. Wright, December 9, 1930.; (Ditto typescript) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to various persons, 1953-. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Letters from various persons to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1953-1957. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Letters from various persons to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1958- and n.d. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Letters from various persons to various persons, 1955-1958 and n.d. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Reviews, releases and clippings discussing the reward for the missing Islandia manuscripts. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Publications
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. All that is poetic in life. Austin Wright's Islandia. Reprinted from Wilson Library Bulletin (vol.31, no.9), May 1957.; ([5]pp.) (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. The Islandian world of Austin Wright. An address to the Zamorano Club. Printed by Merle Armitage, 1957. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Introduction to An Islandian of the Islands. A Field Report by Austin T. Wright, author of Islandia on the Southern California Islands of Santa Rosa and Santa Cruz, written in a letter to his brother, John K. Wright, December 9, 1930. Reprinted from The Southern California Quarterly for the Friends of the UCLA Library (vol.45, no.1), March 1963. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Typescripts (Continued)
    - Wright, J.K. Some comments on Islandia, Lyme, New Hampshire., September 28, 1966.; (7pp. Photocopy typescript) (Box 22, Folder 16)
      Including postcard, October 1, 1966.
    - Felland, Nordis. Obituary for John K. Wright., (Photocopy typescript, 2 leaves) (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Various Publications and Manuscripts
  - Controversial Literature in the University Library (), n.d.
    - n.d., (Carbon copy typescript, 5 leaves) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Projected Biography of Edward M. Kern (), 1939
    - Working Papers--Bibliographies and research notes. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Spindt, H.A. Notes on the Life of Edward M. Kern, Fifth Annual Publication of the Kern County Historical Society. Bakersfield, California, November 1939. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons, 1939-1947. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - The Functions of Rare Books (), 1939
    - Paper read before the College Sub-Section of the Association of College and Reference Librarians at the American Library Association Conference, San Francisco., June 1939.; (Carbon copy typescript, 18 leaves) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Reprinted from College and Research Libraries, December 1939. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - John Fiske--Bookman (), 1941
    - Letter and autobiography by John Fiske and a news item about his library. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographies and research notes. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Paper Read on June 23, 1941, at the meeting of the Bibliographical Society of America, Boston, Massachusetts., (Original holograph draft, 40 leaves, some written on both sides) (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons, 1940-1942. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell, from various persons, 1944-. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Letters to and from various persons, 1940-1946. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. John Fiske--Bookman [Separate from the Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America (vol.35, 4th Quarter), ]., 1941 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Resources of Western Libraries for Research in History (), 1942
    - Correspondence and notes from Lawrence A. Harper to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1942. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Reprint from Pacific Historical Review (vol.11, no.3), September 1942.; (pp.263-280) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography of Gregg Anderson (), 1949
    Powell, Lawrence Clark, comp.
    - Imprints., (5 leaves) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography of Gregg Anderson, 1926-1942. From To Remember Gregg Anderson. Los Angeles: Cole-Holmquist Press, 1949.; (Unbound leaves) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Education for Academic Librarianship (), 1949
    - []., 1949; (Ditto typescript) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Remarks at the Dedication of the Pasadena City College Library (), 1949
    - October 30, 1949., (Carbon copy typescript, 3 leaves) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies, Subject and National (), 1951
    - Foreword by Robert Lewis Collison (New York: Hafner Publishing Company, )., 1951; (Holograph, 2 leaves) (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Original holograph draft.
    - Collison, Robert Lewis. Bibliographies, Subject and National; A Guide to their contents, arrangement and use. London: C. Lockwood, 1951.; (168pp.) (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Page proofs.
      Lawrence Clark Powell used these proofs in preparation of his foreword to the American edition.
    - Correspondence between Crosby Lockwood and son, Limited, and Lawrence Clark Powell, 1951. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Collison, Robert L. Bibliographies, Subject and National with a foreword by Lawrence Clark Powell. New York: Hafner Publishing Company, 1951. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Projected Bookhunter in Britain (), 1951
    - Printed material. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      re Lawrence Clark Powell's trip to Europe.
      Working papers, notes, and plans.
    - Bookman in Britain., (Typescript, 205 leaves) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - The Human Side of Bookplates (), 1951
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Preface, 1951.; (1 leaf) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - 1951., (158pp.) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Music into Silence (), 1951
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to The Pacific Spectator, 1951-1953. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Letters from The Pacific Spectator to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1950-1953. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. Music into Silence., (Carbon copy typescript, 13 leaves) (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Also, galley proofs (3 leaves).
      Also, press release by The Pacific Spectator. Mimeographed letter (1 leaf).
    - Music into Silence. Reprinted from The Pacific Spectator, Winter 1951. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Music into Silence. In Santa Barbara Home Life, December 1951 and January 1952. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - An Obstinate Exile (), 1951
    - Letters from Laurie Lee to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1950-1952. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to Laurie Lee, 1950-1951. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Letters from Lawrence Clark Powell to various persons, 1952-1953. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Letters from various persons to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1951-1953. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Publications by Laurie Lee
      - An Obstinate Exile with an introductory note by Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles: W.M. Cheney, 1951.; (iv, 14pp.) (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Two Birds from a Spanish Cage. In The Listener, December 11, 1952.; (p.987) (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Variations on a Dead Sparrow. In Nimbus (vol.2, no.1). London, June-August 1953.; (pp.44-47) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Land of Fiction (), 1951